

Status: M.Sc. Digital Media, Scientific Employee
Fields: Software Engineering, Consulting, Scrum, Usability

Techs: Meteor, Javascript, Mongo,. Bootstrap, Bash, Git, Webstorm

Activities: Global Game Jam, Open Source, Fitness

Bremen, Germany www.jankuester.com info@jankuester.com +49 176 \*\*\* \*\*\* \*\*

## Summary

Digital media graduate with project experience in the field of technology based assessment. Currently working as IT Consultant at We4IT, Bremen in the field of IBM Notes Domino and XPages applications. Master studies focused on teams from different disciplines and cultural backgrounds on solutions for complex problems.

## Experience

Experience	
Scientific Employee / PhD Student - University of Bremen	2016 - presen
Develop and evaluate the next generation learning management system with Meteor	
Define a new level of software for classroom management based on an extensive nursing curriculum.	
IT Consultant for IBM XPages and Notes Domino - We4IT GmbH Bremen	2014 - 2016
Realize projects in XPages and We4IT Aveedo, monitor project status, conduct reports Implement the frontend for a BPMN compatible engine within We4IT Aveedo	
Scientific Employee / Software Development - University of Bremen	2012 - 2014
Invented a flexible assessment framework, targeting industrial trainees	
Supervised software development lifecycle, Recruited team members	
Project Management Simulation Training - Getoq Consulting	2011 / 11
Performed a two-day project simulation from management perspective	
Topics included customer contracts, change management, controlling, operational tasks	
Student Assistant / Programmer - otulea.uni-bremen.de	2010 - 201
Realized an online diagnosis platform for workforce literacy development (Flex)	
Modeled software design, implemented various prototypes, conducted usability tests	
Education	
Graduated as M.Sc. Digital Media - University of Bremen	2015 / 0'
Master Thesis: Semi Automated Scoring in Technology Based Assessment	
Developed and evaluated an algorithm for semi automated scoring of spreadsheet data	
Master Project - PrIMA - University of Bremen	2012 - 2013
Co-Invented a touch table application for medical support, co-developed software (Java)	
Formed a scrum team, mainted project dev server (Debian), surveyed target audience	
Master Studies Digital Media - University of Bremen	2012 - 2018
Inter-cultural classes in English, covering special topics in computer science and design Professionalized in research methods, software development and e-assessment	
Semester Abroad - University of Melbourne	2009 - 2010

· Mastered six months of study and trans-cultural experience in Melbourne, Australia · Finished machine programming, information visualization, professional essay writing